SR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

786 619 5583 • javi830810@gmail.com

Solutions-oriented developer. Polyglot. Theorist.

Software Engineer, with 10 years of experience in the software industry, go-getter, and over achiever. Experience in Workforce, Education, Advertising, E-Commerce, Communication Systems, Mobile Marketing. Experienced team leader. Keen on minimalist software, generally dislike ORMs and over engineering.

PROFESIONAL SKILLS

Languages: | Python, C#, JavaScript, PHP

Server Development: NET, ASP.NET MVC, NServiceBus, LINQ, Castle Windsor,

Spring.Net, LINQ, webapp2(Python)

Web Development: JQuery, AngularJS, EmberJS, Backbone, Swagger, REST, SOAP,

Ajax, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bower

Cloud: GoogleAppEngine, Azure, AWS, Heroku

Database Systems: | SQL Server, NoSQL (RavenDB, MongoDB, Redis, Memcached,

Neo4J).

Source Control: | GIT, SVN, Mercurial

Testing: NUnit, Nose (python).

Development Practices: OOP, Functional Programming, CQRS, TDD, Agile (SCRUM,

Kanban), Continuous Integration (Travis, Team City, Capistrano).

Task Automation: | Bash, Grunt

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Kaplan INC

2014 - Present

Education. Backend developer, corporate environment, integration with company's internal APIs and closely worked with Product Owners to convert requirements into features. Architect for Scalebridge.

- Scalebridge. Integration platform that handles processing and post-delivery of messages between separated systems. Communication then happens agnostically and through Scalebridge. Hosted at http://scalebridge.appspot.com/
- KAPx. Learning Platform for online courses. Integration with learning management systems, like Moodle. Multitenant suite where different universities host courses and process student operations like tuitions, credits, grades etc. Hosted at http://kapx.kaplan.com/

Python Swagger Memcached GoogleAppEngine AngularJS Grunt Bower Git

Entrepreneurship. Created a company to support and help to grow my own side projects and ideas.

• iMeet. Platform to support event organization and party planning. It includes a wide range of features to compete, including but not limited to: Dispatch SMS, IVR, Email notifications to groups of people, Crowdfunding API, and Address Book management. Hosted at http://imeet.io/

C# Python AspNetMVC Webapp2 Azure GoogleAppEngine Backbone Grunt Git

Manager of Digital Development at ZubiAd

2013 - 2014

Advertising. Team leader for the in house development and outsourcing. Put in place an infrastructure for internal Software Practices, like source control, cloud hosting, continuous integration.

- HTML5 Ad Campaigns for Yahoo, MSN and Huffington Post full page takeovers, as part of a campaign for Ford Motors.
- Zubiad. Design and implementation of the company website, superb web experience, responsive on desktop, mobile. Hosted at http://www.zubiad.com

C# PHP HTML5 Grunt Capistrano CSS3 ¡Query Git

Software Engineer at JDA Software

2010 - 2013

Workforce. Backend developer, worked on highly used and distributed services. Built REST APIs that interacted with Workforce Platforms (Kronos, Infor), also extensively worked with Communication platforms such us Twilio, Voxeo for the distribution of notifications.

- Orbit. Communications platform, high performance; able to distribute 100 SMS per second and able to handle as many incoming responses. Main architect of this system from scratch built it into a core value for the company.
- Shiftex. Shift Manager for employers. Event based architecture. It's currently handing out more than 3000 work shifts a day to potential employees, in stores like Kolhs and Nike.
- Alerts. Emergency system for the New York and New Jersey Port Authority. Used for high reliability and fast response alert broadcast.
- LSS. Employee Address Book for Lutheran Social Services of Michigan. Manages an average of around 2000 employees' daily updates.

C# AspNetMVC NServiceBus WCF SQLServer RavenDb Memcached Nuget SVN

Ecommerce. Online store for biggest Cuban retailer. This nationwide site produces revenue of \$50K+ monthly. Designed to be themed differently, it supports at the current time different stores all across Cuba. This project is the perfect mockup of an ecommerce suite.

CarlosTercero. Online virtual shop for the biggest Cuban retailer, selling products nationwide.
 Built using best pattern and practices including but not limited, Dependency Injection, NTier design, Domain Driven Design, etc. Hosted at http://www.carlostercero.ca

C# ASP.NET 2.0 SQL Server SVN

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree | Computer Science (GPA of 4.3 of 5) | Jun 2007 | Havana University

Find me on:

Github: http://github.com/javi830810
Twitter: http://twitter.com/javi830810

in LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/javi830810

StackOverflow: http://stackoverflow.com/users/71957/javi830810

Wordpress: http://javi830810.wordpress.com/

^{*} References available upon request.